

Mintra Ruensuk
PhD student at UNIST



Ulsan, South Korea



+82 010 40971979



mintra-ruensuk.github.io



mintra@unist.ac.kr

## About me —

Mintra is a second year PhD student in the Graduate School of Creative Design Engineering at Ulsan National Institute of Science and Technology (UNIST), South Korea. She is a member of Interactions Lab. Mintra's research focus includes social computing, affect detection, and software engineering. Her current research aims to use mobile sensing and interactions to detect transient emotions during the social media use.

# Skills -

Python
Machine Learning
Ruby on Rails
Laravel
D3
HTML5
CSS, Bootstrap
JavaScript
Swift, Andriod
Selenium
SQL
CLI

#### Education

since 2017 Ph.D. in Design Engineering (Human-Computer Interaction)

School of Creative Design Engineering, UNIST, South Korea

Current research title: Detecting Transient Negative Emotions during

Social Media Use on Smartphones

2010-2012 M.Sc. in Computer Science (with specialization in Software Engineer-

ing)

School of Engineering and Technology Asian Institute of Technology, Thailand

Thesis: Voice, Gesture, and Web Interfaces for Human-Robot Inter-

action in Service Environments

2005-2009 B.Sc. in Information Technology (First Class Honour)

Faculty of Information Science and Technology Mahanakorn University of Technology, Thailand

Project: Information Technology Jobs Matching By Groovy on Grails

## **Employment**

2015-2017 Lecturer

Department of Information Technology
Faculty of Business and Technology

Stamford International University, Thailand

2015-2015 Lecturer

Department of Computer Science, Faculty of Science Rajamangala University of Technology Thanyaburi, Thailand

2012-2015 Senior Software Engineer

Think Blue Data, Thailand

2009-2010 Lecturer

Faculty of Information Science and Technology Mahanakorn University of Technology, Thailand

### **Publications**

2019 <u>Mintra Ruensuk</u>, Hyunmi Oh, Eunyong Cheon, Hwajung Hong, Ian

Oakley. Detecting Negative Emotions during Social Media Use on Smartphones, in ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems 2019 Extended Abstracts (CHI'19 EA), Asian CHI

Symposium: Emerging HCI Research Collection, to appear.

2019 Mintra Ruensuk, Jayeong Yoon, Choeun Park. Amor: Supporting

Emerging Adult Couples to Manage Finances for a Common Goal, in ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems 2019 Extended Abstracts (CHI'19 EA), Student Design Competition,

to appear. [13% acceptance]

2019 Sanghyun Ma, Mintra Ruensuk, Chajoong Kim. *Design interventions* 

for promoting the mental health of young academic, in HCI KOREA

2019 conference (HCIK'19), [Research Gate]

2018 Mintra Ruensuk. Detecting Emotions using Smartphone Sensors:

Technique to Raise Self-Awareness for Social Media Users, in ACM International Joint Conference and 2018 International Symposium on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing and Wearable Computers (Ubi-

comp'18), Broadening Participation Workshop [doi]

2017 Sirisilp Kongsilp, Mintra Ruensuk, Matthew N. Dailey, and Takashi Ko-

muro. Tablet Fish Tank Virtual Reality: a Usability Study, in International Conference on Artificial Reality and Telexistence Eurographics

Symposium on Virtual Environments (ICAT-EGVE'17) [doi]

- 2016 <u>Mintra Ruensuk</u>. *An implementation to reduce internal/external inter-ruptions in Agile software development using pomodoro technique*, in 2016 IEEE/ACIS 15th International Conference on Computer and Information Science (ICIS) [doi]
- 2015 <u>Mintra Ruensuk</u>, Buraskorn Yoosuka and Pongpol Nilaphruek. *A Special Capstone Course for Exchange Students on Agile Software Development Using Scrum Methodology*, in PKRU Conference on Development of New and Innovation Research for the AEC
- 2010 <u>Mintra Ruensuk</u>, Woraphon Lilakiatsakun. *Information Technology Jobs Matching By Groovy on Grails*, in Proceedings of Conference on Electrical Engineering/Electronics Computer Telecommunications and Information Technology (ECTI-CARD'2010)

#### Awards & Honors

ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI'19)

Student Design Competition (advance to the second round)

ACM Grant for The 2018 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing (Ubicomp'18)

Conference registration waiver and \$600 travel grant for attending Ubicomp 2018

2017 - 2021 UNIST CDE Scholarship

4 years awarded for tuition and stipend for Ph.D. studies

2010 - 2012 Royal Thai Government Fellowship

2 year awarded for tuition for graduate studies

2005 - 2009 Mahanakorn University of Technology Scholarship 4 year awarded for tuition for undergraduate studies

## Volunteer experience

2019 ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI'19)

Student Volunteer

2018 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous

Computing (Ubicomp'18)

Student Volunteer